#### SENIOR LEAD JAVA DEVELOPER

#### Summary

A full-stack Senior Lead Java Developer with in depth knowledge of server side, client side, cloud, mobile and database technologies, over ten years of programming experience Experienced in designing, integrating and delivering large scale Distributed Systems Expertise in agile methodology and test driven development, Demonstrated ability to mentor and guide a team of software engineers to meet the sprint and psi goals on-time. Specialized in utilizing AWS as the Cloud Platform - includes Cloud Automation, Managed Services More than a decade of experience in designing, implementing and adapting technically sophisticated web applications, APIs using Java/J2EE Expertise in determining customer needs and effectively translating those needs into software solutions. Highlights

- Platforms
- AWS, Linux, Unix, Windows
- Cloud/AWS
- Compute
- EC2, Lamda, ELB, Auto Scaling
- Storage
- S3, EBS
- Database
- Dynamo DB, Elastic Cache (backed by Redis)
- Networking
- VPC, Route 53
- Analytics
- Kinesis, ElasticSearch
- Dev Tooling & Management
- Code Deploy, Cloud Watch, Cloud Formation
- Security
- Identity & Access Management (IAM)
- App Services
- SQS, SNS
- Programming Languages
- Java, J2ee, JavaScript, SQL
- Server Side
- Technologies
- Servlets, JSP, EJB, JMS, JPA, JDBC, JAXB, XML, XSD, OAuth
- Frameworks / Libraries
- Spring, Hibernate, Spring Security, Log4j
- · Application Servers
- WebSphere, JBoss, Tomcat, Jetty
- IDE
- IntelliJ IDEA, RAD, Eclipse
- Build / CI
- Jenkins, Maven, ANT
- Testing / Code Coverage
- JUnit, Sonar, fitnesse, TDD, ATDD
- Monitoring
- AppDynamics, SiteScope, JConsole, JVisualVM
- Web Services/Caching
- SOAP, REST, Memcached
- Client Side / Mobile
- Technologies
- HTML5, CSS3, JSON
- IDE / Tools
- Selenium, NodeJs, JQuery, Mocha JS, Bower
- Relational Databases
- DB2, MySQL, Oracle
- NoSQL Databases
- DynamoDB, ElasticSearch
- Version Control
- Git/Github, Mercurial, SVN

### Experience

Senior Lead Java Developer

July 2011 to Current Leidos Holdings Inc. i1/4 Benton, MS

 JDLink is a suite of application components which helps to communicate, configure the terminal connected to CAN BUS on the machine, for collecting the machine data for better tracking and controlling purposes and to increase the efficiency and productivity of machines manufactured by Deere.

- Working on cloud enablement team to expose and consume data analytics services on AWS.
- Involved in several Sprint/PSI level planning and prioritizing of user stories in agile development process.
- Analyse the user stories and convert to a design and implementation plans.
- Used TDD and ATDD methodologies for development to ensure code quality and continuous integration.
- proposed and performed architectural design changes to improve the performance of the api services Did hackathons to improve the
  availability of applications in rolling deployments and integrated those solutions.
- Mentored and guide the junior engineers to meet the sprint and PSI goals.

# Sr. Java/J2EE Developer

June 2009 to June 2011 Medifast, Inc il/4 OH, State

- Project Description: Automated Merchant Activation is a suite of multiple applications primarily used for boarding merchants.
- This consists of core Java applications, web enabled applications, web services, batch applications, user authorization engine supporting LDAP and custom authentication, workflow engine, pricing engine, reporting engine.
- Worked on migrating existing architecture for legacy system to conform to SOA architecture.
- Architect highly customizable and pluggable web services to interface into various existing functionality both for internal and external users
   Architect new backend platform integration for the batch application with scalable and extensible validation and reporting framework
   Implement various modules and interfaces as part of internal integrations Maintain and develop various enhancements for quarterly releases
   or as part of bug fixes for all applications belonging to the suite Took the initiatives to improve the performance of several applications
   belonging to the suite.

## Java/J2EE Developer

March 2008 to May 2009 Voya i1/4 Scottsdale, AZ

- Symphony is in-house developed solution for Business Process Model (BPM).
- It is an add on product that works in conjunction with EBUS.
- Symphony Workflow Manager Helps to reliably move data from source to destination with support for -State persistence and automatic
  retries, EBUS is the in-house Enterprise Service Bus (ESB), and EBUS allows different platforms /databases to easily communicate with
  each other.
- Involved in System Requirements study and conceptual design for EBUS, symphony applications.
- Developed web applications using Spring MVC Architecture RAD used as Java IDE tool for creating Web services, JAXB bindings.
- Message Routing and JMS messaging was implemented with MDB's listening on MQ Queues.
- Involved in implementing Quartz Job Store for Symphony retries logic, and involved in creating the admin console for managing the scheduled jobs.
- Used Java API for XML Binding (JAXB) to transfer the application data between different layers.

# Java Developer

December 2004 to January 2008 Amentum i1/4 Mossville

- Way2sms.com is a website which enables the subscribed users to send SMS free of cost, gives the user 120 characters for message and rest 40 characters used for ads.
- Wrote the ad engine to inject the ads after user messages based on message contextual words.
- Developed user interface on Jakarta Struts 1.0 Framework using JSP 2.0 and HTML.
- Used Web services (SOAP) for transmission of large blocks of XML data over HTTP.
- Used SMTP protocol and JMS for delivering user messages Used Eclipse for writing code & used CVS for Version control.

### Education

Bachelors of computer science: 05 Master of computer Applications, Andhra University Andhra University India Skills

ad, ads, agile, ANT, API, architectural design, Architect, Business Process, com, conceptual design, CSS3, Client, Version Control, CVS, Databases, Database, Eclipse, EJB, XML, HTML, HTML5, HTTP, DB2, IDE, J2ee, Java, JMS, JSP, JSP 2.0, JavaScript, JBoss, JDBC, JQuery, JSON, LDAP, Linux, listening, Log4j, logic, managing, messaging, Access, Windows, works, MVC, MySQL, Enterprise, Networking, NoSQL, Oracle, DB, pricing, Programming, quality, RAD, Relational Databases, reporting, Routing, Scaling, Servers, Servlets, SMS, SMTP, SOAP, SQL Server, stories, Struts 1.0, Symphony, Tomcat, transmission, Unix, user interface, validation, web applications, website, WebSphere, Workflow